spiedigitallibrary.org 2016-10-31

# Privacy Policy | SPIE

Thank you for visiting the SPIE Digital Library - the gateway to thousands of SPIE papers on optics and photonics. 

Your privacy is important to us. We provide this policy explaining our online information practices and the choices you can make about the information you share with us. The policy also expresses the care with which we treat your personal information. SPIE is committed to respecting your privacy and recognizes your need for appropriate protection and management of personally identifiable information you share with us. 

##  Collection of Non-Personal Information

When you browse the SPIE Digital Library, you do so anonymously. We do not collect personal information - including your e-mail address. We do log your IP address (the Internet address of your computer) to administer access rights and to tell us which parts of our website you visit and how long you spend there. We do not link your IP address to anything personally identifiable. We track what country you are accessing the Internet from, and what time and date you visited. Other information automatically provided to us is the type of computer and operating system you are using. Your browser supplies us with this information. We use this information from our server logs to learn more about our visitors as a group, not about you as an individual. The information helps us identify overall usage patterns and trends on the site.

##  Credit Card Information

We collect your credit card information, such as card number and card expiration date, when you purchase products from the SPIE Digital Library.. We do not store your credit card information.

##  Profiles

[SPIE.org Profiles](https://spie.org/app/profiles/default.aspx) is a feature that allows you to publicly display relevant professional information about yourself on the SPIE.org website. You have the ability to manage what information is displayed in your profile via the SPIE.org Profile tab in My Account (sign in required). You may view, update, add or remove any information forming a part of your SPIE.org Profile at any time. Your public profile contains the following: your name, photo, affiliation/organization, job title, company website, SPIE Member type, SPIE involvement (committees currently serving on, conference chair, etc.), areas of expertise, profile summary, SPIE publications, SPIE conference involvement, and SPIE courses taught. If provided by you, others may also view other relevant publications, conferences, and courses taught, and external websites such as LinkedIn. In addition you may choose to allow others who are logged in to their SPIE accounts view your contact information (mailing addresses, phone, fax) and to send you email by opting into SPIE's private messaging. By adding or modifying information in your SPIE.org Profile you agree to allow SPIE to populate or update other databases maintained by us with this information, as applicable. SPIE reserves the right to remove information from a profile that is deemed inappropriate.

##  Cookies

A cookie is a small file that a web site stores on your computer, which does not collect personal information about you. When you revisit the website, your browser sends information back to the site. Cookies allow websites to maintain certain information such as reference codes that indicate your eligibility for member privileges. Cookies can only store data provided by the server or generated by an explicit user action. Only the site that provides them can read them. You can configure most browsers to notify you when cookies arrive and ask your approval to accept them, or to refuse cookies outright. Most browsers can also delete cookies you may have accepted in the past. Cookies are used in the SPIE Digital Library to create a "session" based on your access privileges.

##  Website Forms

We obtain information you provide to us in online forms such as your name, address, and e-mail address. We may use this information to provide you with information about the products and services offered by SPIE. Online forms are available for customers to request information, products, and services. We collect information about you only if you voluntarily provide contact information within these forms. 

We do not share information with the exception that mailing addresses are sometimes made available for the purposes of receiving relevant information from organizations other than SPIE. Please contact SPIE (see contact information below) if you prefer that your mailing address not be made available to other organizations for the purpose of receiving relevant information. E-mail addresses are never released to third parties as a matter of SPIE policy. 

##  Disclosure

We retain the right to release your personal information to proper authorities when required by law or in good faith believe that we must release the information to:

  1. satisfy a legal order or comply with legal process
  2. defend the rights of SPIE or its affiliates or business partners
  3. protect the personal safety of SPIE employees, agents, affiliates, business partners, customers, or site users.

##  Security

This site has security measures in place to protect against the loss, misuse, and alteration of the information under our control. We have taken the necessary steps to provide a secure server for transmission of sensitive data to and from our site, including your login and password. We encrypt all data (including your credit card number) transmitted through our secure Web server so no one else can read it.

##  Privacy Policy Changes

If we decide to change this Privacy Policy, we will post the revisions so that you will always know what information we gather, how we might use that information, and whether we will disclose it to anyone.

##  Contact SPIE

This privacy policy applies to [http://spiedigitallibrary.org](http://new.spiedigitallibrary.org/index.aspx). It does not apply to websites of any SPIE member, affiliate, section, division, or chapter that SPIE does not own or control. It does not apply to websites operated by organizations or groups who associate themselves in any way with SPIE.

It does not apply to any other websites including those that have hypertext links to   
[http://spiedigitallibrary.org](http://new.spiedigitallibrary.org/index.aspx). If you have any concerns, comments, or questions about this privacy policy please contact SPIE: [SPIEDLSupport@spie.org](mailto:customer_service@spie.org).

Telephone: 1-888-902-0894 (US) or +1-360-685-5580 (International)  
Fax: +1 360 647 1445

SPIE - The International Society for Optical Engineering  
PO Box 10  
Bellingham, WA 98227-0010
